Guide to the Warren Jay Vinton papers, 1932-1969
Vinton, Warren Jay papers, 1932-1969
- Series II. Chief Economist. Office Files [1935-1945]-1949
  - "Density"-Definitions of gross and net residential density, memoranda on density in specific projects, research notes, site plans, memoranda on setting official definition from Nathan Straus, administrator James Routh, Research and Statistics Division, Nov. 8, 1938-May 22, 1940 (Box 28)
  - "Detroit"-Memorandum from National Resources Planning Board, 1942 (Box 1)
  - "Disposition of War Housing"-Determination after war: preliminary report by inter-division postwar committee on postwar dispostion of government owned war housing, extracts from NHA manual, recommendations of National Committee on Housing Emergency and statement on FPHA policy, Juen 26, 1943-April 1947 (Box 13)
  - "Disposition of War Housing"-Disposition [of War Hsg.] miscellaneous, 1943-1945 (Box 13)
  - "'E' Miscellaneous"-correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 1)
  - "Earmarkings-Jan. 1941"-allocation of federal funds, 1937-1941 (Box 13)
  - "'F' Miscellaneous"-correspondence with Ernest Fisher on anniversary celebration, 1944 (Box 20)
  - "Federal Housing Administration, Division of Economics and Statistics"-Technique for a real property survey, July 19, 1935-Aug. 14, 1938, M.C. Pt. I. Survey procedure; Pt. II. Tabulation instructions for dwelling survey; Pt. III. Block Tabulation and General Survey Tables 1-18; Supplement annotated: "WJV in charge of field operations.. ." as a Field Research Supervisor, F.H.A. (Box 14)
  - "FPHA Bulletins-[Federal Public Housing Authority] FPHA Bulletin, Washington, D.C. v. 2 no. 8 (January 1, 1945)-9, 11-14, 17-19 (December 1, 1946); v. 4 no. 2-6 (June 1947), 1945-1947 (Box 13)
  - "FPHA Releases"-[Federal Public Housing Authority] Bulletins, brochures, news releases on public war housing and its disposal and reuse, 1942-1946 (Box 28)
  - "Furniture"-Departmental memoranda on furnishing U.S.H.A. aided defense housing projects, reconsideration when families were housed and data on inclusion of furniture in rent in tenant occupied units, Feb. 18, 1941-Oct. 4, 1943 (Box 2)
  - "'G' Miscellaneous"-correspondence, 1943, 1947 (Box 1)
  - "Greer-Hansen Plan"-Report "Proposed Federal Program for Urban Redevelopment and Housing" and criticism, June-Nov. 1941 (Box 17)
  - "Greenbelt Operating Budgets"-binder of study by Clarence Stein, memoranda, correspondence, Oct. 10-Dec. 5, 1935 (Box 24)
  - "Greendale"-Maps, 1938-1963, draft of report by Jacob Crane "Metropolitan Land Reserves as illustrated by Greendale, Wisc.," reports by Walter Kroenig 1946; 1949; photos by Elbert Peets, 1938-1963 (Box 24)
  - Village of Greendale, Wisc. Map, Jan. 30, 1953 (Box 24)
  - Village of Greendale, Wisc. Study for Development. Map, Sept. 1, 1953 (Box 24)
  - Village of Greendale, Milwaukee Community Development Corp. Map, Sept. 1963 (Box 24)
  - Village of Greendale, Wisc. 2 maps, Nov 1, 1938, May 1, 1938 (Box 24)
  - "Greendale"-Metropolitan Land Reserves (rough draft) as illustrated by Greendale Wisconsin, Jacob Crane, Consultant, Feb. 1937 (Box 24)
  - "Greendale"-Walter Kroenig. Ten Year Financial Report of Greendale, Oct. 1949 (Box 24)
  - "Greendale"-Kroenig, Walter, The Development and Disposition of Greendale Wisconscin Second General Report, TS, MC, Dec. 1946 (Box 24)
  - "Grimm, Peter"-Grimm's Slum Clearance Program, 1936 (Box 1)
  - "'H' Miscellaneous", 1943 (Box 1)
  - "Housing-General"-cost and supply related to income: report analyzing national housing policy in relation to annual costs of shelter and family income, "for use of Judge Sam Rosenman," revised copy, memo on housing costs and defense workers incomes, memo on national housing cost analysis; telegram from Nathan Straus lauding housing cost and analysis as "Masterful and Comprehensive", Oct. 16, 1941-May 14, 1943 (Box 7)
  - "Housing-General"-Statements of California Housing Association prepareed by Catherine Bauer on "Principles for a Redevelopment Program" TS (2 copies), 1942 (Box 1)
  - "Housing Legislation Information Office"-List of members (individual and organizations), broadsides, drafts of pamphlets on Wagner-Steagall Housing Bill and completed copies, ca. 1937 (Box 7)
  - "Hygene of Housing, Committee on"-[Div. of American Public Health Association] Pamphlets, records concerning the appraisal technique for measuring the quality of houisng developed by the Committee incl. report of Commission in 2 sections, 5 parts, Feb. 27, 1942-1946 (Box 3)
  - "Ihlder, John"-2 speeches of correspondence to and from John Ihlder, executive officer, Alley Dwelling Authority for District of Columbia concerning defining "housing," "ability to pay," "subsidy", May 1936-Feb. 1937 (Box 3)
  - "Income Definition"-correspondence, inter-office memoranda concerning data used to estimate net income on low-rent housing needs survey and statement of policy on net income; from William Seaver, Assistant Administrator for Development U.S.H.A., James Rough, Director Research and Statistics, Edith Almer Wood, Consultant Lawrence Bloomberg, Asst. Chief Economist and Planning Officer, Jan. 23, 1941-Oct. 6, 1941 (Box 2)
  - "Income Thirds"-correspondence, memoranda and final statement on determining income thirds and production of new houses on basis of specified cities (different rating as to which group served by private building) with Vinton's recommendation that separate figures be used for urban and rural areas; with Nathan Straus, Leon Keyserlng, Edith Wood, Catherine Bauer, James Routh, Feb. 14-June 25, 1941, Aug. 9, 1946 (Box 2)
  - "Index to Files, Extra Copies of"-"List of Contents of WJV's files," listed alphabetically be headings and sub-headings, PC, June 5, 1945 (Box 1)
  - "International Housing and Town Planning Conference" Correspondence esp. with Carolos Contreras on arrangements for 16th International Congress on Housing and Town Planning held in Mexico City 13-27 Aug. 1939 to which Vinton member of U.S. Delegation and representative of U.S. Housing Authority; program, list of U.S. delegates and report, May 2, 1938-July 1939 (Box 2)
  - "'K' Miscellaneous"-correspondence, 1949 (Box 1)
  - "Keyserling, Leon H."-copies of letters recommending elevation of Keyserling from deputy to Administrator of U.S. Housing Authority; correspondence with Sergei Grimm, Syracuse on policy of "urban redevelopment" and Housing; postwar housing problems, June 1945; Feb. 1, 1942-Aug. 13, 1945 (Box 2)
  - "'L' Miscellaneous"-correspondence with Fulton Lewis on his attack on National Housing Agency, 1944 (Box 20)
  - "Labor Department"-National Conference on Labor Legislation L.D.: Proceedings of National Conference, Feb. 14-15, 1934 (Box 2)
  - 2nd National Conference, October 4-5, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Reports of 3rd National Conference, Nov. 9-11, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Bulletin, December 4, 1936 (Box 2)
  - A.S.P.O. newsletter with annotations, Dec. 1936 (Box 2)
  - "Labor Housing Conference"-All releases L.H.C.: Press releases, reports, resolutions, circulars, annual report 3/20/36 outlining formation of Labor Housing Conference and its role along with R.F.L. supporting concept of public low cost housing, government housing agency, Wagner housing bill, etc. MC, Oct. 1935-October 12, 1937 (Box 2)
  - "Land Aquisitions"-Change in National Housing Agency manual, 1943 (Box 1)
  - "Local Authority Conference"-Material for administrator's conference: Binder of topics to be discussed, 1937 (Box 19)
  - "Local Authority Conference"-Preparatory Material for Local Authority Conference: Schedules and committee reports, Nov.-Dec. 1937 (Box 19)
  - "Local Authority Conferences"-Record of L.A. Conferences: Looseleaf notebook of conference proceedings, Nov. 22-Dec. 1, 1937 (Box 19)
  - "Local Authorities Conference"-Washington Conference between Administrator of U.S.H.A. and representatives of certain local authorities, Nov. 22, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Binder: list of those present, confidential memos, committee assignments, committee reports, TS, MC and MS (Box 3)
  - "Local Authorities Conference"-Washington Second Conference of Local Housing Authorities: Binder has list of those invited, list of those participating, U.S.H.A. preliminary outline of policies and procedures, memos, speeches, material for interviewers, minutes, speeches, TS and MC, Dec. 7-9, 1937 (Box 3)
  - "Low Rent Housing"-Confidential memo on limits of federal government participation, memoranda by Frederick Delano, procedures and statements explaining the public low-rent housing program, Feb. 1936-38, April 14, 1948-July 1949 (Box 2)
  - "Manual-Memoranda, minutes, reports concerning the production of U.S.H.A. manuals under the direction of Vinton, July 25, 1941-Feb. 11, 1942 (Box 3)
  - "Manual on Policy and Procedure"-Procedure on Procedure: Reports, drafts, memoranda on drawing a manual of policy and procedures for F.P.H.A., July 13-Dec. 9, 1942 (Box 3)
  - "Market Analysis and Surveys"-Memoranda, notes report on use of market analysis and surveys to determine housing market, Administrator's order no. 7 transferring research and analysis to Administrator's office 1942, drafts of polciy statement "An Apporach to Local Housing Market Analysis" from Nathan Straus, James Routh, Edith E. Wood, Herbert Emmerick, Philip Klintznick, June 3, 1940-April 31, 1945 (Box 3)
  - "McGill University"-Speech "The Planning of Public Housing" in extension series, School of Architecture, McGill University, Montreal, P.Q., December 14, 1943; 1943-1947 (Box 28)
  - "Miscellaneous Memoranda"-Memoranda to and by Vinton chiefly concerning research subjects and procedures, Feb. 23, 1938-April 8, 1941 (Box 3)
  - "Mutual Ownership Plan for Homes"-Audubon Mutual Ownership Plan Legal Instruments Copy no. 5 Mr. Vinton: Binder of legal instruments between Audobon Mutual Ownership Corp., Camden N.J. and F.P.H.A., indexed, 1943 (Box 19)
  - "Mutual Ownership Plan for Homes"-Mutual Ownership Plan for defense housing, analysis and criticism by Vinton etc., March 21, 1941-Oct. 30, 1944 (Box 19)
  - "Mutual Ownership Plan for Homes"-Mutual Ownership: Correspondence, memoranda on mutual ownership, especially of government built wartime homes, 1941-1944 (Box 19)
  - "Mutual Ownership Plan for Homes-[Mutual Ownership] Correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets on mutual ownership, especially of government built wartime homes and Greenmont, Ohio, 1946-1947 (Box 19)
  - "Mutual Ownership Plan for Homes"-Mutual Ownership Defense Housing Division, Federal Works Agency, Binder containing Division's report by Lawrenc Westbrook including magazine articles, March 7, 1942 (Box 19)
  - "Mutual Ownership Plan for Homes"-Mutual Ownership Plan Legal Instruments: Binder of legal instruments to put mutual ownership plan into effect, indexed, 1943 (Box 19)
  - "Mutual Ownership Plan for Homes"-Report and Studies by W.J.V. [on Mutual Home Ownership Plan]: Report, studies and statistics, 1942 (Box 19)
  - "'N' Miscellaneous"-Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - "National Association of Housing Officials"
    - Annual Meetings N.A.H.O.: Proceedings of organization meeting 1933, program, speech, statement, resolution, MC, TS, Nov. 25, 1933-Nov. 13, 1947 (Box 3)
    - Bulletin 1934-1935 NAHO: Bulletin #10 (May 21, 1934), 21, 29-34, 38, 44-46, 50-76 (Dec. 1935) plus supplements and enclosures (Box 13)
    - Bulletins 1936 NAHO: Bulletin #77 (Jan. 13, 1936)-#103 (Dec. 21, 1936) plus supplements and enclosures, Index bulletins 1-76 by number and subject; Index of bulletins 77-103 by number and by subject (Box 13)
    - Bulletins 1937 NAHO: Bulletins #104 (Jan. 9, 1937)-119, 121-129 (Dec. 27, 1937), plus supplements and enclosures (Box 13)
    - Bulletins 1938-1939 NAHO: Bulletin #130 (Jan. 5, 1938)-134 (May 5, 1939); NAHO News, to supercede regular bulletin began January 1938 (Box 13)
    - Bulletin 1940-Present: Bulletin #135 (May 3, 1940), 137-139, 143-144, 148, 150-151, 153-157 (July 15, 1943), 161 (November 29, 1944)-164 (December 20, 1946), 1940-1946 (Box 13)
    - Federal-Local Relations Committee: Report on meetings, Feb. 28 and Oct. 17, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Housing Program for the United States 1939: Correspondence on appointment and meeting of committee to re-examine National Association Housing Officials 1934 Urban Public Housing statement from Bleecker Marquette Coleman Woodbury; MC draft of re-examination, Oct. 28-Dec. 6, 1939 (Box 28)
    - Housing Program for the U.S. 1941: Outline of restatement of A Housing Program for the United States by N.A.H.O., minutes of Committee on Comprehensive Housing Program (MC), meeting notices, drafts of statements, Jan. 30, 1941-Feb. 23, 1942 (Box 28)
    - Local Authority Letter: Letter #56, Oct. 10, 1947 (Box 1)
    - N.A.H.O. General: Newsletters, correspondence, reports, pamphlets, 1937-1948 (Box 1)
    - N.A.H.O. News: NAHO News v. 1 #1-6 (Feb.-Sept. 1938); v. 2 (1939); index; v. 3 (1-9 January-November 1940); v. 4 (1-3, 5-9 January-December 1941); v. 5 (1-3, 5-10 January-December 1942); v. 6 (1-4, 6-11 January-December 1943); v. 7 (#2-3, 6 February-March, June 1944), Feb. 12, 1938-June 1944 (Box 13)
    - NAHO Postwar Housing Committee 1941-1942: correspondence, drafts concerning report of committee on postwar housing of National Association of Housing Officials, membership lists; from Bleecker marquette, Edmund Bacon, Carl Feiss, Nov. 14, 1941-Dec. 28, 1942 (Box 28)
    - NAHO Postwar Housing Committee 1943: Interim reports of January 1943, March 1943, criticism, suggested table of contents, suggestion on yield insurance, correspondence from Bleecker Marquette and Hugh Pomeroy, Jan. 2-Nov. 23, 1943 (Box 28)
    - NAHO Postwar Housing Committee 1944: Statement of Hugh Pomeroy before Public Buildings and Grounds Committee, House of Representatives, report housing for the United States after the war, correspondence concerning corrections and revisions including Vinton's policy on role of Federal officials, Jan. 12-July 11, 1944 (Box 28)
    - Washington Housing Letter: Washington Housing Letter... to Local Housing Authorities, v. 1 no. 1 (Sept. 11, 1943)-10, 12; v. 2 no. 1-11, 13-14 (Nov. 29, 1944); v. 3 no. 1-5, 9-18, 20-37 (Dec. 3, 1945), 1933-1945 (Box 13)
  - "National Association of Real Estate Boards: Correspondence, news releases, reports, Dec. 7, 1936-July 29, 1949 (Box 17)
  - "National Capital Housing Authority"-District of Columbia 1944-1945 [Legislation]: Hearings before Senate Subcommittee of the Committee on the District of Columbia investigating program of the National Capital Housing Committee 1943-1944, hearings before House Subcommittee on the Judiciary of the Committee on the District of Columbia on bills on the elimination of alley dwellings 1944, Committee print on S. 953 to establish Urban Redevelopment Agency, bill S. 1426 (1945) by House and Senate, April 26, 1943-Sept. 25, 1945 (Box 7)
  - "National Capital Housing Authority"-Miscellaneous: Report of Housing and Rent Control Committee, Federation of Citizens' Association (1943) attacking National Capital Housing Authority under John Ihlder, memoranda and clippings on attack; statement on investigation of NCHA by John Ihlder 1944; extract of Senate Testimony in Pencil Points; report of National Industrial Conference Bard attack NCHA 1945 and responses by Ihlder and Philip Klutznick, Commissioner F.P.H.A., clippings, summary of testimony by opponents of public housing before Burton Committee, Dec. 4, 1943-April 10, 1945 (Box 7)
  - "National Committe of Housing Associations"-Recommendations on war housing, 1943 (Box 1)
  - "National Committtee on Housing, Inc."-Correspondence, reports on defense and postwar housing program and policy, Jan. 1941-Nov. 21, 1946 (Box 17)
  - "National Committee on Housing Inc.-"Tomorrow's Town: publication of the National Committee on the Housing Emergency, Inc.; vo. 1 #1-7, 9-12 (April 1943-March 1944), vol. 2 #1-3 (April-Summer 1944); 1945 and National Committee on Housing Inc., 1943-1946 (Box 17)
  - "National Housing Agency"-Lecture Series: Transcript of lectures, 1944 (Box 1)
  - "National Housing Agency"-Organization orders from office of the Administrator, March 29 1943-April 3, 1947 (Box 17)
  - "National Housing Agency"-Releases-press relaeases, especially on war and veteran's housing, 1945-1947 (Box 1)
  - "National Housing Agency"-Urban Studies Division: Correspondence, extracts from manual on role of Urban Studies Division, Sept. 16, 1942-Aug. 4, 1943 (Box 17)
  - "National Housing Association"-Notice of dissolution of Association, 1936 (Box 1)
  - "National Housing Committee"-Resignation of Catherine Bauer, 1944 (Box 1)
  - "National Public Housing Conference"
    - NPHC-Releases: Releases, reports, pamphlets on public housing and redevelopment and covering legislation, 1944, 1946-Aug. 8, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1944-1945: correspondence reports, analysis of proposed legislation, speeches concerning wartime housing, Taft-Ellender-Wagner Bill (National Housing Bill), payment in bill of tax policy, TS, MC, Feb. 9, 1944-Dec. 22, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1934-1943 N.P.H.C.: conference programs, agenda, speeches, correspondence, memoranda re conferences, meetings with officials, publications concerned with wartime housing, government payments for International Service fee, TS, MC, Sept. 29, 1934-Sept. 8, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1948-1949 N.P.H.C.: (National Public Housing Conference to May 1949, then National Housing Conference) Newsletters, bulletins, membership bulletins, some correspondence, especially covering passing of National Houisng Commission Act, July 1949, Sept. 12, 1948, Jan. 3, 1949-Sept. 1946 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1946-1947: Release and newsletter in favor of public housing program, favoring Taft-Ellender Wagner Bill, rent control, opposing Wo.cott Dispostin Bill, covering different aspects and interest of program, May 20, 1946-Dec. 15, 1947 (Box 2)
    - Public Housing (Bulletins) N.P.H.C.: Public Housing (formerly Public Housing Progress) v. 9 #3-12 (March-Dec. 1943); v. 10 #2-11 (Feb.-Nov. 1944); v. 11 (1945); v. 12 #1-5, 8-9 (Jan.-Sept. 1946); v. 12 #1, 3-4, 6 (Jan.-Nov. 1947); v. 14 #1-2, 5 (Jan.-May 1948); Duplicates, 1943-1948 (Box 13)
    - Public Housing Progress (Bulletins) N.P.H.C.: v. 1 #2 (Dec. 15, 1934), 4-11 (Nov. 15, 1935); v. 2 #1-9 (1935-1936); v. 3 #1-8 (Nov. 1937-June 1937); v. 4 (1937-1938); v. 5 (1938-1939); v. 6 #1-4, 6-8 (1940); v. 7 (1941); v. 8 (1942); v. 9 #1-2 (Jan.-Feb. 1943); Duplicates, 1934-1943 (Box 13)
  - "National Resources Committee"-Correspondence, report, press release, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "National Resource Planning Board"-Housing, Need for: Reports, statements, clippings, memorandum, articles on housing needs and impending shortages by Franklin Roosevelt, Catherine Bauer, Coleman Woodbury, Franklin Delano; Includes National Resources Board confidential report on housing by Catherine Bauer, Woodbury and Edith Wood, 1935, May 1935-Nov. 28, 1945 (Box 7)
  - "New Orleans, La."-Letter and photo, 1944 (Box 1)
  - "New School for Social Research"-Letter to Charles Abrams on policy of New School for Social Research, 1941 (Box 20)
  - "Organization"-Charts and orders on organization of U.S. Housing Authority, June 30, 1939-May 1, 1945 (Box 17)
  - "Organization Charts"-Chart of U.S. Housing Authority's administrative organization 1939-1941, of Federal Public Housing Authority 1942-1946, of Public Housing Administration 1948, # directories of officers of housing administration 1946-1949, Jan. 1, 1939-1949 (Box 3)
  - "Payments in Lieu of Taxes"-PILOT correspondence, memoranda, outlines, statements dealing with tax exemptions on defense housings correspondence with Municipal Finance Officers Association on demand PILOT be raised to 10% of shleter rents, increas announced June 15, 1944, Vinton trip to Chicago November 1943, brief from Boston housing interests, March 1949-Sept. 1949 (Box 4)
  - "Payments in Lieu of Taxes"-NAHO Committee [National Association of Home Officials]: Report of Committee on Housing Subsidy and Finance, "Payments in Lieu of Taxes" MC (2 copies), June 5, 1944 (Box 4)
  - "Post-War Planning"-Correspondence, notes report on urban redevelopment; see also other headings N.H.A. Postwar Discussion Group, 1942-1944 (Box 1)
  - "Progress Charts"-Production Progress: Charts and graph on U.S.H.A. program showing predictions and progress of loan contracts and disbursements; MS of notes of work by Vinton, Jan. 14, 1938-April 15, 1939 (Box 3)
  - "Public Administration Clearing House"-Memorandum of conclusions of Conference on Land Planning and Community Planning, 1946 and invitation to special conference administrative problems in Federal Aid to urban development and redevelopment, 1946-1949 (Box 1)
  - "Public Housing-FPHA Publications"-Public Housing Weekly News (Federal Works Agency, U.S. Housing Authority) v. 1 #1-46 (Aug. 1939-July 1940); v. 2 #1-41 (1940-1941); v. 3 #3-8 (1942), Aug. 11, 1939-April 13, 1942 (Box 4)
  - "Public Works Administration"-George Haley Bill P.W.A.: Printed material concerning Public Act #837 (74th Congress) sponsored by George Healey (Mass.) to authorize payments in lieu of taxes for P.W.A. property and waiving by PWA of policy jurisdiction on their property. Bills, hearings, Congressionl Record, Conference report, act, Feb. 24-June 29, 1936 (Box 4)
  - "Public Works Administration"-Miscellaneous P.W.A.: pamphlets, brochures by P.W.A. on public housing and PWA; Public Works Administration, MC bulletins on public housing and Wagner-Steagall Housing Act, offpring from Architectural Record March 1935 "How the P.W.A. Housing Division Works" by Col. H.B. Hackett, also by Col. Hackett "Municipal Cooperation Aids PWA's Program of Slum Clearance and Low-Rent Housing" in American City, Feb. 1935, and Alfred Fellheimer "Low-Rent housing.. .Planning American Standards for Low-Rent Housing "in American Architect, ca. 1935-1938 (Box 4)
  - "Public Works Administration"-P.W.A. Housing Division-History: Brief History of Housing Division (MC) June 16, 1933-Oct. 30, 1937; Brief History of Housing Division with regard to limited dividend projects (MC) Aug. 17, 1933-Juned 19, 1937; Financial History of Houisng Divising (MC) Oct. 30, 1937; Allotment History Report (MC) Oct. 31, 1937; ERA Condensed Allotment Record (MC) Oct. 31, 1937; ERA Condensed Allotment Record (MC) Oct. 31, 1937; Condensed Allotment Record NIR (MC) Oct. 31, 1937, June 16, 1933-Oct. 31, 1937 (Box 4)
  - "Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands"-Correspondence, clippings, pamphlets concerned with Vinton's trip as delegate of U.S.H.A. to Puerto Rico to inaugural ceremonies on slum clearance of San Juan and Ponce., Dec. 11, 1939-Feb. 3, 1940 (Box 4)
  - "United States Housing Authority"-President's Lists: List of low-rent housing and slum clearance projects for presidential approval, P.C.; List #1, March 17, 1938 and covering letter signed by President Roosevelt (Box 17)
  - "President's List"-Act. Chief Proj. Review Reports on the President's List #1: Binder of farms for approval of contract for low-rent housing and slum clearance projects; included report and computation of capital financing and annual contributions (see also box 17), March 16, 1938-Jan. 3, 1939 (Box 19)
  - "President's Lists"-Act. Chief Project Review Reports on the President's List #1: Binder of project applications for presidential approval, 1939 (Box 17)
  - "President's Lists"-Summary Reports for President's List #14: Approvals of project applications by U.S.H.A., 1939 (Box 17)
  - "President's Lists"-Summary Reports on the President's Defense List #4: Binder of project applications approved U.S.H.A., indexed, 1940 (Box 17)
  - "President's Lists"-Summary Reports on the President's Defense List #28: Approvals of project applications by U.S.H.A., 1940 (Box 17)
  - "President's Lists"-Summary Reports on the President's Defense List #5: Binder of project applications, approved by U.S.H.A., indexed, 1941 (Box 17)